Guide to the University of Chicago. Renaissance Seminar. Records 1963-1976
University of Chicago Library
University of Chicago. Renaissance Seminar. Records
1963-1976
.5 linear ft. (2 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Renaissance Seminar Records consist of correspondence between Seminar leaders Edward Lowinsky and Eric Cochrane, Seminar participants and guest lecturers (1964-1976). The collection also includes minutes, membership lists, and meeting notices (1964-1976).
Information on Use
Access
No restrictions.
Historical Note
The Renaissance Seminar began in 1963 at the University of Chicago. The group was founded by Edward Lowinsky, the Ferdinand Schevill Distinguished Service Professor of Music at the University of Chicago. The Seminar attracted participants from colleges and universities throughout the Midwest.
Scope Note
The Renaissance Seminar Records consist of correspondence between Seminar leaders Edward Lowinsky and Eric Cochrane, Seminar participants and guest lecturers (1964-1976). The collection also includes minutes, membership lists, and meeting notices (1964-1976).
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Subject Headings
Cochrane, Eric W.; Lowinsky, Edward E. (Edward Elias), 1908-1985; University of Chicago. Renaissance Seminar; Renaissance -- Congresses
INVENTORY
- Lowinsky Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lowinsky Correspondence, A-H, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Lowinsky Correspondence, H-Z, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lowinsky Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Lowinsky Correspondence, A-H, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lowinsky Correspondence, J-Q, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lowinsky Correspondence, R-Z, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cochrane Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Minutes, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Member Lists and Meeting Announcements, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Member Lists and Meeting Announcements, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Member Lists and Meeting Announcements, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Member Lists and Meeting Announcements, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Member's Biographical Information, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- "The Renaissance Seminar, The University of Chicago, 1963-1973," Report, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)